That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
Episode 13: The Great Clash
（リムル）
リザードマンの首領と同盟を結び
オークと戦うべく
We're on our way to the
marshlands to sign a treaty
with the Lizardman chieftain
and fight the Orc army.
俺たちは湿地帯に向かっている
出陣するメンバーは
The ones accompanying me are
Benimaru, Shion, Hakurou,
ベニマル シオン ハクロウ
and Souei, who's out scouting.
そして 偵察中のソウエイ
There's also Ranga...
それに ランガと…
（ランガ）ワフッ
and our Goblin riders.
（リムル）
ゴブリンライダーだ
Oh, and we've left Rigurd and
the rest to watch the village.
ちなみに
村は リグルドたちに任せてある
The plan is that they'll
flee immediately if we lose.
俺たちが負けたら
即座に逃げてもらう手筈(てはず)だ
Great Rimuru, a moment?
（交信:ソウエイ）
リムル様 よろしいですか？
What's up, Souei?
（リムル）
ん… どうした？　ソウエイ
I've come across two groups
currently engaged in battle.
（ソウエイ）
交戦中の一団を発見しました
One of them is a personal guard
to the Lizardman chieftain.
片方は
リザードマンの首領の側近です
They appear to be fighting a high-ranking Orc.
相手は
オークの上位個体のようですね
What action shall I take?
いかがいたしましょう？
Well, I mean...
（リムル）
“いかが”って…
We have to help them, don't we?
助けないわけにはいかないだろう
Can you win?
勝てるか？
A simple task.
（ソウエイ）
たやすいことかと
He didn't even hesitate!
（リムル）
即答かよ！
イケメンだから有能ですってか？
So being a hottie makes him skilled, too?
Do it. We'll be there soon.
（交信:リムル）
やれ　俺たちも すぐ行く
Understood.
（ソウエイ）
御意
Assume battle formation.
We're going to meet Souei!
（リムル）
戦闘態勢を取れ！
ソウエイのもとへ向かうぞ
Sir!
（一同）はっ！
（ゴブタ）やるっす！
Let's do this!
ランガ！
Ranga!
（ランガ）仰せのままに！
As you command!
Er, what? It's already over?
（ゴブタ）あ… あれ？
（ゴブタ）もう終わってるっすか？
He should've left some for us...
（ベニマル）
少しは残しといてくれよ
（ハクロウ）ふ〜む…
（リムル）
あら〜
Oh, boy. That Souei really is skilled.
ソウエイのヤツ
マジで有能だったよ
深手を負っています
She is gravely injured.
Okay.
安心しろ 回復薬だ
Don't worry. It's healing potion.
えっ？　きっ 傷が…
M-My wound... I thought it was fatal.
致命傷だと思ったのに
Wh-Who are you?
あ… あなたは？
俺はリムル＝テンペスト
I'm Rimuru Tempest.
I must ask a favor of you!
（ガビルの妹）お願いがございます
Please save my father, the Lizardman
chieftain, and my brother Gabiru!
我が父たるリザードマンの首領と
兄たるガビルを
どうか お救いくださいませ！
ガビルの妹なのか？
You're Gabiru's sister?
I am.
What happened?
（リムル）何があった？
（ガビルの妹）
兄 ガビルが謀反を起こし
首領を幽閉したのです
My brother led a rebellion
and imprisoned the chieftain.
I believe he intends to repel
the Orc army on his own,
兄は オーク軍を
自らの力で
退けるつもりのようです
ですが
but he has underestimated the Orc Lord.
兄は オークロードを
甘く見ており
このままでは
リザードマンは
If we take no action, the Lizardmen
will surely be exterminated.
滅亡することに
なりましょう
My father helped me escape during
a lapse in the guard's attention.
父は見張りの隙を見て
私を逃がしてくれました
I am aware that this is a selfish request,
先走らぬようにとの約定(やくじょう)も守れず
after we broke our promise to wait for you,
虫のいい話であるのは
重々承知しております
but I implore mercy from you who
serve such a powerful majin!
しかし…
力ある魔人の皆様を従える
あなた様の
その慈悲にすがりたく
Please... Please!
何とぞ… 何とぞ！
Well said, indeed!
（シオン）よくぞ申しました
That you recognize our
leader Rimuru's greatness
リムル様の偉大さに気付くとは…
あなたは見どころがあります
means you have potential!
H-Hey, Shion...
おっ おい シオン…
Come now, stand up.
（シオン）さあ 立ちなさい
あなたの希望どおり
リザードマンは救われるでしょう！
I'm certain the Lizardmen can
be saved, just as you hoped!
Whoa, whoa...
（ガビルの妹）
ありがとうございます…
ありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you!
The way she just accepts
work for me on her own...
（リムル）
勝手に仕事を取ってくる
この感じ…
Thank you! Thank you! Thank you!
She's definitely a secretary.
まさに秘書だな
What choice do we have? We'll be
fighting the Orc Lord, either way.
しかたない
どうせオークロードとは戦うんだ
So, um... You're the chieftain's
daughter, you say?
え〜っと
君は首領の娘さんだっけ？
Y-Yes, sir!
は… はい！
I am at your command.
仰せのとおりにございます
Then I'll acknowledge you as a
representative of the chieftain.
（リムル）
では 君を首領の代理と認める
Do you object to forging an
alliance right here and now?
ここで同盟を締結することに
異論はあるか？
No, not at all!
いえ！　異論など
じゃあ 決まりだ
同盟は締結された
Then it's settled. The alliance is complete.
Thank you so much.
（ガビルの妹）
ありがとう… ございます
Souei, can you use Shadow Movement
to get to the chieftain from here?
ソウエイ お前
首領の所まで“影移動”できるか？
もちろんです
Of course.
I so envy your skills...
有能で 羨ましいよ
リザードマンの首領救出を命じる
I'm ordering the rescue
of the Lizardman chieftain.
（ソウエイ）御意
Understood.
感謝いたします
You have my gratitude.
俺たちは進軍を続けるぞ！
The rest of us will continue our march!
Sir!
Trample all! Trample all! Trample all!
（オークたち）
蹂躙(じゅうりん)せよ！　蹂躙せよ！
蹂躙せよ！　蹂躙せよ！
蹂躙せよ！
Mere Orcs are no match for us Lizardmen!
（ガビル）
オークなど
我らリザードマンの敵ではない
Right! Withdraw for now!
よし　一旦 離脱！
Our plan was to toy with them
（ガビル）
我らが翻弄し
and have the Goblins finish them off,
ゴブリンたちに
しとめさせるつもりであったが…
but it looks like we won't
even need the Goblins' help.
ゴブリンたちの手を借りる必要も
なさそうであるな
What's happening?
（ガビル）何だ？
オークが… オークを食っている！
The Orcs... are eating other Orcs?
た… 助けて〜！
H-Help!
S-Sir G-Gabiru—
ガビル… ガビル様！
Retreat! Now!
（ガビル）退却だ！　急げ！
退却〜！
Retreat!
Sir Gabiru, we're already surrounded!
ガビル様！
回り込まれちゃったよ！
なに！
What?!
（ガビル）
何が起こった？
What just happened?
They're clearly moving faster now!
明らかに
ヤツらの動きが素早くなっている
Impossible! Webbed feet
and scales on an Orc?!
（ガビル）
バカな！
オークの体に 水かきと鱗(うろこ)だと？
That makes them just like us!
それでは まるで
我らと同じではないか！
（部下）
さっき 仲間が１人 食われた！
They just ate one of our men!
Indeed! It was then that
their movements changed!
しかり！
そこから ヤツらの動きが変わった
（ガビル）
ぐっ… まさか
食うことによって我らの能力を！
Are they gaining our powers by eating us?!
ぐう…
群れ全体か…
The entire horde...
Maintain close formation!
密集隊形！
Keep the Goblins in the center!
Leave no space between you!
ゴブリン隊を中央に
隙なく固まれ！
ゴブリン隊を守りつつ
オークの包囲を突破する！
Shield the Goblins while breaking
through the Orcs' formation!
（ガビル）
我らだけなら
逃げきれたかもしれんが…
If it was just us, perhaps
we could have escaped,
but bringing the Goblins
worked against us in the end!
ゴブリンたちを連れてきたことが
裏目に出てしまった
Trample all! Trample all!
（オークたち）
蹂躙せよ！　蹂躙せよ！
Our allies' powers will become our own!
仲間の力を我が物に
The enemy's powers will become our own!
ヤツらの力を我が物に
恐れるな！
Do not fear!
Trample all! Trample all!
我ら誇り高きリザードマンの力を
見せつけてやれ！
Show them the strength upon which
we Lizardmen pride ourselves!
Our allies' powers will become our own!
Yeah!
Wh-What an intimidating aura...
な… なんという
すさまじいオーラであるか
そこのオーク！
You, Orc!
You are the Orc Lord, correct?
貴様がオークロードであるな
我が輩は
リザードマンの首領 ガビル！
I am Gabiru, chieftain of the Lizardmen!
Face me one-on-one to settle this—
我が輩と 一騎打ちで決着を…
I am not the Lord.
（オークジェネラル）
ロードではない
I am an Orc General.
（オークジェネラル）
我はオークジェネラル
オークロード様の足元にも及ばぬ
I am far inferior to the great Orc Lord.
オークロードではない？
You're not the Orc Lord?
Even with this much power,
he's still far inferior?
（ガビル）
これほどの力を持ちながら
足元にも及ばないだと？
You wish to fight one-on-one?
（オークジェネラル）
一騎打ちだったか？
面白い
Interesting.
I accept.
受けてやろう
I thank you!
感謝する！
Just what kind of monster
is the real Orc Lord, then?!
（ガビル）
一体
どれほどの化け物だというのだ
本当のオークロードとは！
Yes! Yes!
（ラプラス）
よ〜っしゃ よっしゃ〜！
This is going great! Right, Lord Gelmud?
いい感じになってきたで〜
なあ ゲルミュッド様
Indeed.
（ゲルミュッド）うむ
Looks like everything's
going according to plan!
（ラプラス）
計画のほう
順調に運んどるようやな〜 ハハッ
It won't be long before my child
gains dominion over the forest.
（ゲルミュッド）
我が子が森の覇権を手に入れる日も
近いだろう
And then my ambition will—
そうなれば 俺の野望も…
You seem to be having quite a fun time.
（トレイニー）
なかなか楽しそうな話を
していますね
Who's there?!
（ラプラス）誰や！
（トレイニー）私の名はトレイニー
My name is Treyni.
I cannot overlook malicious
scheming in this forest.
この森での悪だくみは見逃せません
This isn't good, Lord Gelmud!
（ラプラス）
こりゃ ヤバいぞ ゲルミュッド様
That's a Dryad! They're the
caretakers of the forest!
森の管理者 ドライアドや！
What?!
（ゲルミュッド）なんだと！
森を乱した罪で
あなた方を排除します
For the disruption you've caused,
I am removing you from this forest.
Huh?!
精霊召喚 シルフィード
Spirit summoning: Sylphide!
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
You're jumpin' the gun a bit here!
（ラプラス）
待て待て 待て待て！
気ぃ早すぎやろ
断罪の時です
罪を悔いて祈りなさい
The time for judgment has come.
Pray in repentance for your sins.
Aerial Blade!
エアリアルブレード！
H-Hey! Your arm!
（ゲルミュッド）
おっ おい！　う… 腕！
（ラプラス）
むちゃくちゃしよるな あんた
You're crazy, lady.
We don't even get a say in this?
問答無用かいな
Well, we've already achieved
our goal, anyway...
まあ 目的は達成しとるし…
so we'll just be gettin' out of here.
わいらは おいとまさせてもらうわ
So long, now!
ほな さいなら！
They escaped...
逃げられましたか…
This is not a desirable outcome.
状況は思わしくありません
リムル＝テンペスト
Rimuru Tempest, I am trusting
you to defeat the Orc Lord.
オークロードの討伐･…
信じていますよ
（ガビル）ぐおお！
Vortex Crash!
ボルテクスクラッシュ！
ふん！
Chaos Eater!
カオスイーター！
You're trying to eat me?
我が輩を食おうというのか！
（オークジェネラル）
グッフッフ…
いつまで逃げきれるかな
Do you think you can keep running forever?
S-Sir Gabiru!
ガ… ガビル様！
We will help!
助太刀を！
Stay out of this!
（ガビル）手を出すな！
（３人）あっ…
I'll handle this one-on-one!
これは 一騎打ちである！
漢(おとこ)だぜ ガビル！
You're such a man, Gabiru!
Gabiru!
ガビル〜！
ガビル！
Gabiru! Gabiru! Gabiru!
（部下たち）ガビル！　ガビル！
ガビル！　ガビル！
（オークジェネラル）ふん！
これしき…
This is nothing!
とう！
（オークジェネラル）なに？
What?
（ガビル）でやあああ！
うっ！　ぐうう…
Sir Gabiru!
ガビル様！
トカゲは 地面を
はいつくばっているのが
Lizards are best suited
to crawling on the ground.
お似合いだ
死ねい！
Now die!
Y-You're... the true leader of that village!
き… 貴殿は
あの村の真の主(あるじ)殿ではないか！
（ゴブタ）
何 言ってるっすか？　この人…
What's this guy talking about?
Have you come to save us?!
（ガビル）
もしや 我々の助太刀に？
（ランガ）
あれは
ゴブリンライダーの隊長 ゴブタだ
That's Gobta, captain of the Goblin riders.
牙狼族(がろうぞく)の！
The Direwolf!
My name is Ranga.
（ランガ）我が名はランガ
I've come to help you on
my master Rimuru's orders.
リムル様の命(めい)により 助太刀に来た
いかにして ここまで…
How did you get here?
Shadow Movement.
Are you incapable of learning?
（ランガ）
“影移動”だ
学ばんのか 貴様
（オークジェネラル）
グッフッフ… リムルだと？
Rimuru, you say?
I don't know who any of you are,
どこの馬の骨かは知らんが
but if you will stand in
my way, I will show no—
邪魔立てするなら 容赦は…
（ゴブタ）
おっと… 始まったみたいっすね
Oh, looks like it's started.
The great magic of the Lizardmen?
（オークジェネラル）
リザードマンの大魔法か…
I must end this quickly
早々にケリをつけて
and end whoever is using great magic!
大魔法を操る者を始末せねば！
ぬうう…
ええっと…
So, um... Gabiru, was it?
（ゴブタ）ガビルさんでしたっけ？
（ガビル）ぬっ
さっさと防御陣形を整えるっすよ
We should assume a defensive formation.
（ガビル）
ぬっ 分かったのである
しかし…
I understand, but...
What are those flames?
（ガビル）あの炎は…
（ゴブタ）
心配いらないっす
味方の術っすから
No need to worry. They're on our side...
（ゴブタ）多分
I think.
This is why I told you to move.
（ベニマル）
だから どけと言ったろ
Wh-Who are you?!
（オーク）き… 貴様ら 何者だ！
You don't remember us? That's harsh.
（ベニマル）
覚えてないのか？　ひどいな
里を
食い散らかしてくれたじゃないか
You devoured our village, remember?
Those horns... Are you Ogres?!
その角 まさか… オーガか？
どうかな？
Are we, now?
That might not be quite true anymore.
今は少し違うかもしれないな
It is time.
（ハクロウ）いよいよじゃな
（シオン）
この機会を与えてくださった
リムル様に 感謝いたします
We must thank Great Rimuru for
giving us this opportunity.
I'll say it once more.
（ベニマル）
もう一度 言う
道を空けろ 豚ども
Move out of the way, pigs...
灰すら残さず消えたくなければな
unless you want to be
wiped out without a trace.
Wow...
すっげえな
（オークジェネラル）フン！
It appears you've come to assist the lizards,
トカゲどもを助けに来たらしいが
ムダなことを
but you waste your time.
ゴブリンに 犬畜生
Goblins and dogs, the arrival of
worthless monsters such as yourselves
どこぞの木っ端魔物の配下が
加わったところで
will not sway our superiority in the least!
我らの優勢は少しも揺るがんわ！
“木っ端”って…
Worthless?!
We will show you, then.
（ランガ）では 見せてやろう
（ゴブタ）え？
H-Huh?!
（リムル）何… これ？
What is this?
（大賢者(だいけんじゃ)）
解(かい)…
Answer. This is the individual Ranga's
wide-range attack, Death Storm.
個体名ランガの
広範囲攻撃技
デスストームです
（リムル）あ… そう
Oh... I see.
Curse you!
おのれ〜！
テンペストスターウルフに
なったっす！
He turned into a Tempest Star Wolf!
Do you see now, Orcs?!
（ランガ）
よく見たか オークどもよ
This is a mere fraction of the power of
the one you mocked as being worthless!
これが
貴様らが木っ端と侮ったお方の
力の一端だ！
It blew everything away...
（ゴブタ）
全部 吹っ飛んじゃったっすよ
Yes!
これが俺たちの新たなる門出
This our brand new beginning.
Of Great Rimuru's many
glorious victories in war...
リムル様の華々しい勝ち戦の…
This will be the first, you see!
まずは最初の１戦目… ですね
調子に乗るな〜！
Don't get cocky!
えい！
フウ…
Great Rimuru!
リムル様〜！
Y-Yeah...
I hope I never piss her off.
（リムル）
シオンを怒らせるのは やめよう
But anyway...
それにしても…
That overwhelming Orc army
is shrinking before my eyes.
圧倒的だったオーク軍が
みるみる減っていく
I guess those Kijin really are a major asset.
ホントに鬼人(きじん)勢は優秀だね
Man, I hope they'll still want to
be friends after this war's over.
いやはや…
この戦いが終わったあとも
仲良くしたいものだね
I wonder how things are going for Souei...
ソウエイも うまくやってるかな？
（斬る音）
（オーク）ぎゃあああ！
（リザードマン）
うう… 助かったのか？
We're... alive?
（ソウエイ）これを使え
（ガビルの妹）あっ…
Use this.
Father!
（ガビルの妹）父上！
来てくださったのか ソウエイ殿
You truly came for us, Souei!
But why?
（首領）しかし なぜ…
The alliance was formed.
（ソウエイ）同盟は締結された
And how did...
それは どういう…
（ガビルの妹）
私を首領の代理と
認めてくださったのです
I was acknowledged as your representative.
援軍が来ます
Reinforcements are coming.
なんと…
Truly?
まだ諦めるときでは
ありません 父上！
It is not yet time to give up, Father!
（首領）一族は… 助かるのか？
Our people will be saved?
Souei!
ソウエイ殿！
No need to worry.
（ソウエイ）心配いらない
I've already rendered him immobile.
既に動けなくしてある
そういう反応になりますよね
One can't help but react
that way, it seems...
My... My decision...
（首領）
わ… わしの判断は
My decision to accept this alliance...
同盟を受け入れるという判断は…
正解だった
was the correct choice!
見えてるな？　オークを操る者よ
You can see this, can't you,
puppet master of the Orcs?
You will be next.
次は貴様の番だ
オーガの里を滅ぼし
鬼人を敵に回したこと
Destroying the Ogres' village
and making enemies of the Kijin
せいぜい後悔するがいい
will be your greatest regrets.
Damn them all!
（ゲルミュッド）
クソどもが！　役立たずめ！
Useless fools!
Kijin, he said?
鬼人だと？
I did have Geld attack
a large Ogre village...
ゲルドには
オーガどもの里を襲わせたが…
まさか 生き残りが進化したとでも
いうのか？
Does this mean the survivors
of that village evolved?!
And that huge animal!
それに あの獣だ
No one told me there was a beast
like that in the Forest of Jura!
ジュラの森に あんな化け物が
いるなど聞いてないぞ
What in the world is happening
outside my notice?!
俺が知らぬところで
一体 何が起きているというのだ！
This is bad! I must do something...
マズい… なんとかしなければ
or my plans will fall
apart after coming so far!
ここまで来た計画が潰れてしまう！
If this goes on, I'll be...
（ゲルミュッド）
このままでは 俺が…
I'll be killed... by him!
俺が あの方に殺されてしまう！
I found the Orc Lord!
（交信:リムル）
いたぞ オークロードだ
Right!
（オークロード）腹が減った
I'm hungry...
I want to eat something... anything!
何でもいい… 食いたい！
Orc Lord...
（リムル）オークロードよ…
I'm going to put an end to you.
引導を渡してやる
Next time, "The One Who Devours All."
（大賢者）
次回「全てを喰(く)らう者」
The One Who Devours All